RUCHIKA KUSKAR

Contact No: 7666090206 / 7058533870

E-mail:ruchika.kuskar84@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ruchika-kuskar-8499rsk

Summary:

Recruiter with a demonstrated history of working in IT/Non-IT Skilled in Python (Programming Language), C++, Communication, English, and Engineering. Strong human resources with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused in Electronic and telecommunication from Government College Of Engineering And Research Avasari Khurd

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Sr. No	EXAMINATION	UNIVERSITY/ BOARD	PASSING YEAR	PERCENTAGE
1	MBA-HR	YCM	MAY 2024	Pursuing
2	BE ENTC	SPPU	AUGUST 2022	8.04 CGPA
3	H.S.C	Maharashtra State board	2017	74.00 %
4	S.S.C	CBSE	2015	8.6 CGPA

SKILLS:

- Operating system Known: Windows XP/7/8,10.
- □ Programming Language: C, C++,PYTHON
- ☐ Web Development: HTML
- Basics of machine learning & Data Science
- Human Resource Management
- □ Recruitment

Work Experience:

Technical Recruiter at Krehsst Tech Solution, Koregaon Park Pune: July 2022-

Present

Working as Technical Recruiter for Manufacturing & IT industries Sourcer (July 2022-March 2023)
Recruiter (March 2023-June 2023)

Roles & Responsibilites:

- 1. Sourcing candidates using the Naukri portal
- 2. Screening & shortlisting the candidate by telephonic call
- 3. Upload their details & relevance on ATS(Tallite)
- 4. Follow up with candidates till they get offered

Recruitment Executive at HyringNinja: Jan 2022-June 2022

Working as recruiter for both IT/Non-IT companies IT Profile work on :DevOps Engineer,Data Scientist,Data Engineer,Staff UI,Computer Vision Engineer,Backend cloud developer,Cloud solution Architect

Non-IT Profile work on: Alliance Manager, Sales Development Representative, Enterprise Sales Manager

Roles & Responsibilites:

- 1. Identify the hiring needs
- 2. Prepare job descriptions
- 3. Devise recruitment strategy(Job Posting and advertising)
- 4. Screen and shortlist candidates
- 5. Schedule interviews
- 6. Documentation and follow up till joining

INTERNSHIP:

HR recruiter at Career Job Solution: Aug 2021 - Sept 2021

We worked as a recruiter for both IT Non-IT companies for profiles like sales, AC, SDE, Telecaller, etc. For that we used method such as

- Sourcing candidate from Job portals i.e. Job posting and Data
- Screening resumes & short-listing candidate.
- Take telephonic rounds of Interview.
- Schedule their next rounds of interviews.
- Maintain record of short-listed candidates.

We worked as JR.HR Manager in newtonhouseel which is edu-tech platform, for newtonhouseel we hire student promoter from different cities who bring registrations for our talent hunt test. For this we used methods like Job posting, screening, shortlisting, interviewing and training

Data science intern at Sciffer Analytics Baner: Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

As a Data Science Intern we worked on projects using NLP, AL, ML, DS using basic python coding. We worked on Image detection, Audio detection, Emotion detection, etc.

Certification:

- 1)Microsoft Technology Associate: Introduction to python programming
- 2)Data science using python from Remark Skill
- 3)Human Resource Management (Basics)

Project:

1) <u>Uber data analysis :</u>

Description: We made use of libraries such as pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, Scipy. We collect data and sort them using numpy and then visualize the data graphically using matplot and seaborn and then draw predicted and absolute value.

2)Smart Parking System using IOT:

Language used: HTML, CSS, php mydmin

Description: We create a web page for registeration of slot booking in online mode then with the help of hardware we design our Smart parking model, connect the database to microcontroller and web page

3) <u>Human Resource Management</u>

Description: As a part of glossaread HR we source candidate from different colleges & job portal, screen their resumes, interview them & after successful completion of this we train them as their post & also As BDE we develop and sell our educational

product to student at affordable price.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Name :	RUCHIKA SAI	NJAY KUSKAR

□ Date Of Birth: 8th APRIL 1999

☐ Father Name : SANJAY KUSKAR

 \square Father Profession: VICE-PRINCIPAL

☐ Gender: FEMALE

□ Nationality: Indian□ Religion: Hindu

☐ *Marital Status*: *Unmarried*.

Language Known: English, Hindi, Marathi.

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

(RUCHIKA SANJAY KUSKAR)